<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Animation on Alex Knows Data</title>
    <link>/categories/animation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Animation on Alex Knows Data</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/animation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Airrohr Finedust Data Analysis</title>
      <link>/post/finedust/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/finedust/</guid>
      <description>In einem Twitter thread habe ich über DIY Feinstaubsensoren berichtet. Hier der Inhalt:
Laut airrohr Daten überschritten viele Hamburger Sensoren in 2018 regelmäßig den zulässigen PM10 Tagesmittelwert von 50 µg/m³. Beispiel: Am 23.11.18 (KW 47) überschritten 182 von 205 Sensoren (89%) den Grenzwert.
Laut EU-Richtlinie sind max. 35 Grenzwertüberschreitungen pro Sensor und Jahr zulässig. Laut airrohr Daten überschritten in 2018 dennoch 43 Sensoren den Grenzwert häufiger als 35 Mal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Bot Open Data Hamburg</title>
      <link>/post/opendata/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/opendata/</guid>
      <description>I have build a twitter bot that tweets everytime a new dataset is being uploaded on the Open Data Portal of Hamburg. You can find the code behind the bot on my Github. It is sheduled via a cronjob on a virtual machine on Google Cloud Platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data journalism with Spiegel Online</title>
      <link>/post/ddj/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ddj/</guid>
      <description>Between August and September 2018 I had the chance to support some data journalism projects at Spiegel Online as part of my Google Fellowship. Here is a list of things I have worked on during my fellowship:
Blackbox SchufaDeutschland sprichtAuswärtstorregel</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#airrohr</title>
      <link>/post/airrohr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/airrohr/</guid>
      <description>I installed my own open source fine dust sensor on my balcony in September 2017. I build this sensor as part of a bigger citizen science project called luftdaten.info. The data from all fine dust sensors is also available here. By March 2018 I was wondering how many fine dust sensors we have in Hamburg so I created an animated visualization of the project growth in Hamburg. It’s all made with #rstats.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>